[
    {
        "id": "300000",
        "question": "In Python 3, the maximum value for an integer is 263 - 1:",
        "optionA": "True.",
        "optionB": "False",
        "answer": "False"
       
    },
    {   "id": "300001",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "optionA": "Wick van Rossum",
        "optionB": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "optionC": "Guido van Rossum",
        "optionD": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "Guido van Rossum"
       
    },
    {
        "id": "300002",
        "question": "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
        "optionA": "object-oriented programming",
        "optionB": "structured programming",
        "optionC": "functional programming",
        "optionD": "all of the mentioned",
        "answer": " all of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        "id": "300003",
        "question": "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
        "optionA": "No",
        "optionB": "Yes",
        "optionC": "machine dependent",
        "optionD": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "id": "300004",
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
        "optionA": ".python",
        "optionB": ".pl",
        "optionC": ".py",
        "optionD": ".p",
        "answer": ".py"
    },
    {
        "id": "300005",
        "question": "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
        "optionA": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
        "optionB": "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
        "optionC": "Python code is only compiled",
        "optionD": "Python code is only interpreted",
        "answer": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300006",
        "question": "All keywords in Python are in _________",
        "optionA": "Capitalized",
        "optionB": "lower case",
        "optionC": "UPPER CASE",
        "optionD": "None of the mentioned",
        "answer": "None of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        "id": "300007",
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
        "optionA": "Indentation",
        "optionB": "Key",
        "optionC": "Brackets",
        "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
        "answer": "Indentation"
    },
    {
        "id": "300008",
        "question": "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
        "optionA": "Function",
        "optionB": "def",
        "optionC": "Fun",
        "optionD": "Define",
        "answer": "def"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300009",
        "question": "Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
        "optionA": "//",
        "optionB": "#",
        "optionC": "!",
        "optionD": "/*",
        "answer": "#"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300010",
        "question": "Which of the following functions can help us to find the version of python that we are currently working on?",
        "optionA": "sys.version(1)",
        "optionB": "sys.version(0)",
        "optionC": "sys.version()",
        "optionD": "sys.version",
        "answer": "sys.version"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300011",
        "question": "Python supports the creation of anonymous functions at runtime, using a construct called __________",
        "optionA": "pi",
        "optionB": "anonymous",
        "optionC": "lambda",
        "optionD": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": "lambda"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300012",
        "question": "What is the order of precedence in python?",
        "optionA": "Exponential, Parentheses, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
        "optionB": "Exponential, Parentheses, Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction",
        "optionC": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Subtraction, Addition",
        "optionD": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction",
        "answer": "Parentheses, Exponential, Multiplication, Division, Addition, Subtraction"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300013",
        "question": "What will be the output of the following - x>>2 - if x=1?  ",
        "optionA": "4",
        "optionB": "2",
        "optionC": "1",
        "optionD": "8",
        "answer": "4"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300014",
        "question": "What does pip stand for python?",
        "optionA": "Pip Installs Python",
        "optionB": "Pip Installs Packages",
        "optionC": "Preferred Installer Program",
        "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
        "answer": "Preferred Installer Program"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300015",
        "question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
        "optionA": "underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed",
        "optionB": "unlimited length",
        "optionC": "all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
        "optionD": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": "unlimited length"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300016",
        "question": "Which of the following is the truncation division operator in Python?",
        "optionA": "|",
        "optionB": "//",
        "optionC": "/",
        "optionD": "%",
        "answer": "//"
    
    },
    {   "id": "300017",
        "question": "Which of the following is the truncation division operator in Python?",
        "optionA": "|",
        "optionB": "//",
        "optionC": "/",
        "optionD": "%",
        "answer": "//"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300018",
        "question": "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
        "optionA": "factorial()",
        "optionB": "print()",
        "optionC": "seed()",
        "optionD": "sqrt()",
        "answer": "print()"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300019",
        "question": "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
        "optionA": "Every object doesn’t have a unique id",
        "optionB": "Id returns the identity of the object",
        "optionC": "All of the mentioned",
        "optionD": "None of the mentioned",
        "answer": "Id returns the identity of the object"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300020",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a core data type in Python programming?",
        "optionA": "Tuples",
        "optionB": "Lists",
        "optionC": "Class",
        "optionD": "Dictionary",
        "answer": "Class"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300021",
        "question": "Which of these is the definition for packages in Python?",
        "optionA": "A set of main modules",
        "optionB": "A folder of python modules",
        "optionC": "A number of files containing Python definitions and statements",
        "optionD": "A set of programs making use of Python modules",
        "answer": "A folder of python modules"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300022",
        "question": "What is the order of namespaces in which Python looks for an identifier?",
        "optionA": "Python first searches the built-in namespace, then the global namespace and finally the local namespace",
        "optionB": "Python first searches the built-in namespace, then the local namespace and finally the global namespace",
        "optionC": "Python first searches the local namespace, then the global namespace and finally the built-in namespace",
        "optionD": "Python first searches the global namespace, then the local namespace and finally the built-in namespace",
        "answer": "Python first searches the local namespace, then the global namespace and finally the built-in namespace"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300023",
        "question": "Which function is called when the following Python program is executed - f = foo() format(f) ?",
        "optionA": "str()",
        "optionB": "format()",
        "optionC": "__str__()",
        "optionD": "__format__()",
        "answer": "__str__()"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300024",
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a keyword in Python language?",
        "optionA": "pass",
        "optionB": "eval",
        "optionC": "assert",
        "optionD": "nonlocal",
        "answer": "eval"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300025",
        "question": "Which module in the python standard library parses options received from the command line?",
        "optionA": "getarg",
        "optionB": "getopt",
        "optionC": "main",
        "optionD": "os",
        "answer": "getopt"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300026",
        "question": "What arithmetic operators cannot be used with strings in Python?",
        "optionA": "*",
        "optionB": "-",
        "optionC": "+",
        "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
        "answer": "-"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300027",
        "question": "Which of the following statements is used to create an empty set in Python?",
        "optionA": "()",
        "optionB": "[]",
        "optionC": "{}",
        "optionD": "set()",
        "answer": "set()"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300028",
        "question": "To add a new element to a list we use which Python command?",
        "optionA": "list1.addEnd(5)",
        "optionB": "list1.addLast(5)",
        "optionC": "list1.append(5)",
        "optionD": "list1.add(5)",
        "answer": "list1.append(5)"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300029",
        "question": "Which one of the following is the use of function in python?",
        "optionA": "Functions don’t provide better modularity for your application",
        "optionB": "you can’t also create your own functions",
        "optionC": "Functions are reusable pieces of program",
        "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
        "answer": "Functions are reusable pieces of program"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300030",
        "question": "What are the two main types of functions in Python?",
        "optionA": "System function",
        "optionB": "Custom function",
        "optionC": "Built-in function & User defined function",
        "optionD": "User function",
        "answer": "Built-in function & User defined function"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300031",
        "question": "Which of the following is a Python tuple?",
        "optionA": "{1, 2, 3}",
        "optionB": "{}",
        "optionC": "[1, 2, 3]",
        "optionD": "(1, 2, 3)",
        "answer": "(1, 2, 3)"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300032",
        "question": "What will be the output of the following Python expression round(4.576)?",
        "optionA": "4",
        "optionB": "4.6",
        "optionC": "5",
        "optionD": "4.5",
        "answer": "5"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300033",
        "question": "Which of the following is a feature of Python DocString?",
        "optionA": "In Python all functions should have a docstring",
        "optionB": "Docstrings can be accessed by the __doc__ attribute on objects",
        "optionC": "It provides a convenient way of associating documentation with Python modules, functions, classes, and methods",
        "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
        "answer": "All of the mentioned"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300034",
        "question": "What is output of print(math.pow(3, 2))?",
        "optionA": "9.0",
        "optionB": "None",
        "optionC": "9",
        "optionD": "None of the mentioned",
        "answer": "9.0"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300035",
        "question": "The process of pickling in Python includes ____________?",
        "optionA": "conversion of a Python object hierarchy into byte stream",
        "optionB": "conversion of a datatable into a list",
        "optionC": "conversion of a byte stream into Python object hierarchy",
        "optionD": "conversion of a list into a datatable",
        "answer": "conversion of a Python object hierarchy into byte stream"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300036",
        "question": "What is the maximum possible length of an identifier?",
        "optionA": "31 characters",
        "optionB": "63 characters",
        "optionC": "79 characters",
        "optionD": "None of the mentioned",
        "answer": "None of the mentioned"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300037",
        "question": "Which of the following is invalid?",
        "optionA": "_a = 1",
        "optionB": "__a = 1",
        "optionC": "__str__ = 1",
        "optionD": "None of the mentioned",
        "answer": "None of the mentioned"
    
    },
    {
        "id": "300038",
        "question": "Which of the following is an invalid variable?",
        "optionA": "my_string_1",
        "optionB": "1st_string",
        "optionC": "foo",
        "optionD": "_",
        "answer": "1st_string"
    
    }
]